Andrew Nicholson

 $nicholsons of tware @gmail.com \bullet linked in.com/in/and rewnicholsons of tware \bullet github.com/anicholson 44$

I bring over 10 years of high impact experience consistently driving high priority projects to success, leading by example and mentorship, and continually my teams with compounding results. My goal is to work with great engineers and leaders to create great products that make lives better.

Work Experience

Founding Engineer / Staff Software Engineer at Rula Mental Health • 12/2021 - 03/2024, remote

- Joined as engineer #3
- Built **foundational services and products**, including a resilient email system, partnership integrations, and web portal products for both patients and therapists
- Drove cross-functional initiatives including a process to develop an SDLC and an org-wide reference architecture based on Domain-Driven Design, Event-Driven Architecture, and Command/Query Responsibility Segregation
- Implemented a Transactional Outbox and Durable Workflow Execution Environment to provide the team with solutions to widespread distributed systems problems

Staff Software Engineer at Sift • 01/2021 - 12/2021, remote

- Joined through the 2021 acquisition of ChargeBack
- Designed and **led development of a new data architecture** to enable flexible product support for customers, **unblocking business scalability**
- Worked closely with product managers to shape our low-code business rules platform

Senior Full-Stack React/Ruby on Rails Engineer and Team Lead at Spatial Networks • 03/2020 - 12/2020, remote

- Led development and took ownership over project success for a strategic low-code platform feature using Ruby on Rails, React, and Postgresql
- Provided technical leadership and mentorship in the company's product-focused engineering team
- Advocated for industry best practices around DevSecOps and drove a cultural shift to adopt new processes
 in line with those best practices, including Kanban, automated testing, and CI/CD

Full-Stack React/C# Engineer at Pluralsight, LLC • 11/2018 - 11/2019 in Salt Lake City, UT and remote

- Joined throught the 2019 acquisition of GitPrime, Inc.
- Delivered high-visibility, strategic integration between GitPrime and Pluralsight
- Engineered web applications with TypeScript, React, Redux, C#, and PostgreSQL

Full-Stack React/Ruby on Rails Developer at SciMed Solutions, Inc. • 02/2016 - 11/2018 in Durham, NC and remote

- Engineered web applications for clients in agricultural and medical research
- Consistently delivered high-quality software for SciMed's biggest clients using React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, and SQL databases

Full-Stack JEE Developer at Red Hat, Inc. • 08/2013 - 06/2015 in Richmond, VA and remote

- Contributed to high priority projects
- Mentored junior developers

Software Developer Intern at Noblis, Inc. • 06/2012 - 01/2013 in Danville, VA and remote

• Led development of a Grails web application that displayed results from computations run on a Cray XMT2 supercomputer

Technical Expertise

```
8+ years - Ruby on Rails • Postgres • React • AWS • JavaScript 5+ years - TypeScript
```

```
3+ years - NodeJS • AMQP 2+ years - Java 1+ years - Kafka
```

Personal Projects

systemicity.blog • 06/2024 - present

- Technical blog that aims to simplify complex topics in distributed systems and software organizations camsizes.com 01/2020 present
 - Rock climbing gear comparison tool, used by many climbers to compare climbing cams made by different manufacturers

Education

University of Virginia, College of Arts and Sciences • 08/2009 – 05/2013, Charlottesville, VA BA in Computer Science and Philosophy